Let's have a look at our current burger application state, in the checkout page in the contact data
u andaki burger uygulama durumumuza kontak veri konteyneri zerindeki check out sayfasndan bakalm,
container there, if we have a look at that container,
o konteynere bir gz atalm.
we see that we got some general state set up at the top of the page and we of course also in there have
Sayfann st ksmnda bir genel durumu belirlediimizi gryoruz ve elbette ayrca sipariimizi
our submit method where we submit our order to a server and where we also pass some data.
bir sunucuya gnderdiimiz ve bize veriyi gnderdiimiz gnderim yntemimiz var.
Now the customer data which is set up here is not suited to this state at all,
imdi burada ayarlanan mteri verileri bu eyalete hi uymuyor.
actually not even the fields are equal,
Aslnda alanlar bile eit deildir.
now part of that module will be to sync that up but also if we have a look at the form itself, we
imdi bu modln bir ksm ilki toplamak iin ok yaknda olacak, ancak foruma bir gz
have a couple of the normal input elements there,
attmzda orada birka normal girdi esi var.
leave aside that they're not even styled,
Skmadklarn bir kenara brakn.
we don't really handle their input,
Onlarn giriini gerekten ele almamaktayz.
we don't really handle when the value changes, leave alone that we would validate the input the user
Deer deiiklikleri tek bana brakldnda kullanclarn gittii girdiyi dorulamamz gerektiinde bunu gerekten
left.
ele almamaktayz.
So the first step is that we will have to decide which kind of data do we need, that we then store this
Bu nedenle ilk adm, hangi veri trlerine ihtiyacmz olduuna karar vermek zorunda kalacaz,
in the state then it would be best if we even find a way of dynamically generating our form
bylece bunu duruma kaydettiimizde dinamik olarak formumuzu retmenin bir yolu bulursak daha iyi olur.
and that of course is a last step, of course not only handle the form submission but also to handle the
son adm olarak ya da yalnzca form gnderme ilemini gerekletirmekle kalmaz, ayn zamanda form
form validity or check the form validity and change the styling of our form based on the validity for
geerliliini ele alr ya da form geerliliini kontrol eder ve rnein geerliliine dayanarak formumuzun biimini deitirir.
example.
Ve elbette
These are all things I want to do and for that, I'll start by putting these input elements here into
Bunlarn hepsi yapmak ve ilerlemek istediim eyler ve DS girdi elerini burada standart bir tasarma sahip standart
custom components which have a standardized styling, maybe have a default label and also later will be
bir tasarma sahip standart bileenlere koyarak balayacam ve belki varsaylan bir etikete sahip olabilir ve daha sonra
extended to have room for error messages.
hata mesaj alanna sahip olacak ekilde geniletilecektir.
So one step after the other, let's start by putting inputs into their own component.
Dolaysyla birbiri ardna bir adm nde kendi bileenine girdi koyarak balayalm.